Personal Particulars

Name In Full : Teo He Xiang, Ivan

Passport / NRIC # : \$8825340 Z

Nationality : Singaporean

Personal Email Address : <u>ivan.teo1507@gmail.com</u>

Mobile (Local) : 9696 5748

Address : Blk 357, Clementi Ave 2 #06-275

Singapore 120357

Availability : 1 month notice



Summary

Accountancy major with outstanding academic results and 3 years experience in auditing financial institutions. Proven ability to excel in fast-paced environment. Self-disciplined and meticulous with strengths in time management, organisation and team-work skills. Possesses good communication and interpersonal skills, a keen eye for details and problem solving skills.

Professional Experience

Ernst & Young LLP Sep 2013 – Present

Audit Senior Associate

- Performed financial audit mainly on banks and asset managers
- Analyzed financial statements based on knowledge of entity's business, external market conditions, regulatory environment and macro-economic environment
- Identified weaknesses in internal controls and recommended solutions to address these weaknesses and mitigate risks
- Performed compliance audit to assess adherence with local laws and regulations such as Monetary Authority of Singapore Regulations, AML/CFT regulations, Singapore Financial Reporting Standards and Singapore Companies Act
- Involved in the preparation of audited financial statements as well as the audit report.

Alfa Laval Aalborg Pte Ltd

Nov 2012 - Jan 2013

Accounts Assistant

- Cleared backlog of vendors' accounts statements reconciliation and ensured subsequent statements are reconciled on a timely basis; allowing internal control to function effectively and efficiently
- Prepared monthly balance sheet schedules and reconciled differences ensuring accurate recording of balances
- Performed journal entries, accurately allocated costs to appropriate ledgers
- Assisted in petty cash disbursements, staff claims and supplier payments allowing timely settlement
- · Lightened overall workload on finance department, thereby helping them cope with the external audit

Dynacast (S) Pte Ltd Nov 2011 – Jan 2012

Accounts Assistant (AP)

- Responsible for reconciling vendors' accounts statements to ensure timely settlement of accounts and resolution of dispute

- Performed a high volume of accurate journal entries into Syspro, allowing invoices to be captured in the correct period and accounts to be closed on time
- · Reorganised filling system resulting in more efficient retrieval of archives

Allianz Reinsurance Asia Pacific Branch

Sep - Dec 2010

Underwriting Assistant

- Managed the department's portfolio ensuring relevant information is available when it is due for review;
 enabling the department to consistently meet deadlines thus improving customer satisfaction
- Oversaw premium collection and coordinated with Accounts Department on accounting related issues allowing timely resolution
- Supported the Regional Manager in preparation of monthly forecasts
- Maintained customer database via SalesForce (CRM & Cloud Computing)

Academic Background

CPA Australia

 CPA
 2016 - Present

 Associate Member
 2013 - 2016

Achieved High Distinction in the following Professional Papers:

- Ethics & Governance
- Financial Reporting
- Strategic Management Accounting
- Advance Audit and Assurance

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology | Singapore

2011 - 2013

Bachelor of Business (Accountancy) with Distinction

Awarded letter of commendation for being amongst top 5 students in:

- Introductory Accounting
- Management Accounting and Business
- Cost Management and Applications
- Financial Accounting
- Singapore Company Law

Singapore Polytechnic | Singapore

2005 - 2008

Diploma in Biotechnology

Extra Curriculum Activities

Singapore Polytechnic Symphonic Band

2005 – 2008

Saxophonist

Performed in the band's annual "I Believe in Music" and "Musical Delights", successfully raising funds

Additional Information

Languages:

· Fluent in English and Mandarin

IT Skills:

- Proficient in Microsoft Office Open Office
- · Exposure to MYOB in course of study
- · Working knowledge on Microsoft Axapta and SysPro (Accounts Payable Module)

Military Service: Underwater Combat Medic (Navy)

- Conducted regular reviews on standard operating procedures
- · Managed a team in screening pre-enlistees and regulars in their medical reviews
- As secretary in the Naval Underwater Medical Committee, prepared and disseminated meeting minutes, coordinated subsequent meets and organized LIFE activities